SHAHBAZ TARIQ

Android Developer

SUMMARY:

Android Developer with a solid foundation in native Android app development using Java/Kotlin and a growing portfolio of published apps. Over 8 remote paid/unpaid internships, I've developed 25+ apps from scratch, managed production-level apps, and worked on my own apps which are published on Google Play.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Android Developer, CloudAsset

(Aug 2024 - Present)

As the only Android Developer here:

- ➤ Upgraded SDK from versions 31-33 to 34, resolving dependency issues in 5 apps.
- ➤ Added in-app Update feature in 3 Apps.
- ➤ Integrated Search Functionality in all 3 Apps based on requirements (search based on Policy or Quotes)
- ➤ Changed various behaviors of these 5 apps as required by the client/QA team.
- Migrated 2 Apps from ButterKnife to ViewBinding.
- Fixed various Firebase Crashlytics errors/crashes, improving stability of all 5 apps.

Android Developer, Freelancer

(Mar 2024 - July 2024)

- Developed a Kotlin-based cow farm management app with NFC technology from design to deployment.
- Fixed bugs and implemented updates for a Java-based car parking app according to new requirements.

Android Intern (Remote), Wenawa

(Jan 2024 - Feb 2024)

- ➤ Bug fixes, UI changes, Maintenance of 4 production level apps in Kotlin/Java
- Apps were: Quran App, Photo Animation App, Women's Fitness App, ChatBot App.

Android Intern (Remote) at CodeAlpha, CodSoft, CodeClause, Prodigy InfoTech, InternSavy,

CodersCave, Internee.pk

(Sept 2023 - Jan 2024)

- Developed Apps: ChatBot, Weather, TodoList, Inventory, UnscrambleGame, Tripify, QuizGame,
- FlashCards, TicTacToe, ContactsManager, Calculator, Internee.pk, QuotesGenerator, StudentsPortal

PROJECTS:

- 1. Islamic Dua Muslims Prayers: (Live on Google Play Store with 4000+ Downloads) [Link]
- Features Categorized Duas for various occasions with search, favorites, and dark mode options.
- 2. MooVate: (For a Freelance client)
- Daily Milk logging farm app using Kotlin, Firebase and NFC Technology.

EDUCATION:

	BS in Software Engineering,	University of Karachi (UBIT	(2021 – 2024))
--	-----------------------------	-----------------------------	---------------	---

➤ DAE in Computer Information Technology, Aligarh Institute of Technology (2017 – 2020)

➤ ACCP Pro Diploma, Aptech, Karachi, Pakistan (2017 – 2020)

SKILLS:

Android SDK	Android Studio	Kotlin	Java	Navigation Component
Firebase	Google Maps	ViewBinding	DataBinding	MVVM Architecture
API Integration	Retrofit	XML	Coroutines	SQLite (Room DB)
Animations	Git/Github	SourceTree	OOP	Dependency Injection
Hilt	NFC Integration	Jira	Admob ads	Play Store Deployment
Live Data	Work Manager	Paging	Proguard/R8	Jetpack Compose (Learning)